[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]
The second approach we see when dealing with missing data is purification by
والطريقة الثانية التي نواجهها عند التعامل مع البيانات المفقودة هي التنقية،
what's called imputation.
وذلك من خلال ما يسمى بالتعويض.
It's filling in the missing values with question marks
حيث يتم وضع علامات استفهام مكان القيم المفقودة
with some best guesses of what might have happened.
من خلال أفضل تخمينات عن ماذا حدث.
I'm personally not a hoarder.
وأنا شخصيًا لست شخصًا مكتنزًا،
I don't collect a lot of things.
فأنا لا أجمع الكثير من الأشياء،
I don't really care about stuff that much.
أنا لا آبه للأشياء كثيرًا،
But when it comes to data, I really feel bad about throwing it away.
ولكن عندما يتعلق الأمر بالبيانات، فأنا أشعر لا أشعر بحال جيدة عند إهمالها.
I don't want to throw away data.
أنا لا أريد فقدان البيانات.
And so going down from nine data points to six data points, this pains me.
وعندما ننحدر من تسع نقاط بيانات إلى ست نقاط بيانات فذلك يؤلمني.
I don't think it's a really good idea.
أنا لا أعتقد أن ذلك فكرة سديدة.
Imputation is an alternative to this.
والتعويض بديل لذلك.
It's to say, okay, instead of throwing away those question marks,
وكأن لسان حاله يقول، بدلاً من تضييع علامات الاستفهام تلك،
let's try to get a best guess of where that question mark value might be and
دعونا نحاول الحصول على أفضل تخمينات حول القيمة التي يمكن أن تكون عليها علامة الاستفهام
just fill in those values.
ووضعها فقط مكان هذه القيم.
And this is the kind of approach you might take.
وهذا هو نوع الطريقة التي ستتخذها.
You take your input data which might have some missing values in it.
حيث ستقوم بأخذ بيانات المدخلات لديك والتي قد يكون بها بعض القيم المفقودة،
You take your best guess at filling in those missing values and
وستقوم بأفضل تخمين عند وضعها مكان هذه القيم المفقودة
now you have a data set where everything has been filled in.
وسيكون لديك الآن مجموعة بيانات، تم ملأ كل ما فيها.
For example, in a nine row data set here we have these three question marks.
على سبيل المثال، لدينا في مجموعة البيانات ذات التسع صفوف، ثلاث علامات استفهام.
And we could say the term is unknown for these three question marks.
ويمكنك ملاحظة أن الأجل غير معروف لعلامات الاستفهام تلك.
When I fill in those values with my best guess which might be three year loan.
وعندما أقوم بملأ هذه القيم بأفضل تخمين لدي والذي يمكن أن يكون قرض بأجل 3 سنوات.
For the three values over here.
للثلاث قيم الموجودة هنا.
Why did I choose three year loan to fill it in?
لماذا أخترت القرض لأجل ثلاث سنوات لملؤه؟
Well if you look at the original data set,
حسنا إذا نظرت إلى مجموعة البيانات الأصلية،
there were four three year loans versus two five year loans,
هناك 4 قروض لأجل ثلاث سنوات مقابل 2 قرض لأجل خمس سنوات،
so four here was my best guess.
لذا فإن 4 هنا هي أفضل تخمين.
And you can think about it as my best simple guess.
ويمكنك اعتبارها كتخميني الأبسط والأفضل.
So I just took a simple approach,
لذا فقد اتخذت للتو طريقة سهلة،
just whatever was most popular I filled those in.
لذا، مهما كان الأكثر شيوعًا، فقد قمت بملئهم به.
So the way that imputation might work in this simple approach,
لذا، فإن الطريقة التي قد يعمل بها التعويض من خلال هذه الطريقة المبسطة،
the rule might say for categorical data like of excellent, fair,
فإن لسان حال القاعدة يقول، إن البيانات الفئوية مثل ممتاز ومقبول وضعيف
poor, three year, five year.
والأجل لثلاث سنوات أو لخمس سنوات.
You just put in the most popular value and it's called the mode of distribution.
فـأنت للتو وضعتها في القيمة الأكثر شيوعًا وهي ما تسمى بالتوزيع،
For numerical data,
للبيانات الرقمية،
I would suggest you put in either the average or the median value.
أود أن أقترح عليك أن تضع إما متوسط أو قيمة وسيطة.
Now, these are just simple logistics.
والآن، تلك فقط بعض اللوجستيات البسيطة.
There're many more advanced and interesting ways to impute missing values.
وهناك العديد من الطرق الأكثر تقدمًا ومتعة لتعويض القيم المفقودة.
There's something called expectation-maximization,
وهناك ما يسمى تحقيق أقصى قدر للتوقع،
or Algorithm, which is an algorithm that does this in a very interesting way.
أو الخوارزمية التي تقوم بذلك بطريقة ممتعة للغاية.
Now we just described a very simple thing in this course.
ولقد قمنا بذلك بوصف شيء بسيط جدًا في هذه الدورة التدريبية.
Addressing missing data by imputation has advantages and disadvantages.
لتقديم البيانات المفقودة من خلال التعويض مميزات وعيوب.
It's easy to understand and implement.
فهي من السهل فهمها وتطبيقها.
It can be applied to any model because after you fill in your data you just fit
حيث يمكن تطبيقها على أي نموذج لأنك بعد أن تقوم بملأ بياناتك
in to any algorithm you have you don't have to modify anything, so that's great.
تقوم فقط بملاءمتها لأي خوارزمية ولا تحتاج لأي تعديل، لذلك فهذا أمر ممتع.
And it can be used as a prediction type because whenever you hit a question mark
ويمكن استخدامها كنوع للتنبؤ،
you fill it in in the same way that you did with the training data.
لأنك في أي مرة تواجه فيها علامة استفهام، تقوم بملئها بنفس الطريقة التي قمت باستخدامها في بيانات التدريب.
So if you have a question mark for term you just fill it in three years,
تقوم بملئها بنفس الطريقة التي قمت باستخدامها في بيانات التدريب.
three alone is just like it did in the training data.
ثلاث سنوات فقط، كتلك التي وضعتها في بيانات التدريب.
So that's great.
لذا فهذا رائع.
However, imputation like this, especially a simple imputation that I describe,
ومع ذلك، فإن التعويض الذي يكون كذلك وخصوصًا التعويض البسيط الذي قمت بوصفه،
can be extremely problematic, because it introduces a bias.
قد يكون إشكاليًا للغاية، حيث أنه يقدم تحيزًا.
Every question mark in term will put in three years.
سيتم وضع أجل بثلاث سنوات مكان كل علامة استفهام.
We then use any other information we plug in the same value.
ثم نستخدم أي معلومات أخرى قمنا بتوصيلها لنفس القيمة.
And this could result into really bad systematic errors.
ويمكن أن ينتج عن ذلك أخطاء منهجية سيئة للغاية.
So step back and take an example.
لذا تراجع خطوة للوراء واتخذ مثالاً،
I live in the state of Washington in the US, and let's say that in the state of
أنني أعيش في واشنطن في الولايات المتحدة،
Washington it's illegal to put the age into the loan application.
دعونا نقل إنه في ولاية واشنطن من غير القانوني وضع السن في طلب القرض.
That means that if the loan applications come from the state of Washington,
وهذا يعني أنه إذا كانت طلبات الحصول على القروض تأتي من ولاية واشنطن،
age is always a question mark.
فإن السن دائماً سيكون عبارة عن علامة استفهام.
In other states maybe not a question mark, but age is always a question mark here.
وربما لا يكون السن في باقي الولايات عبارة استفهام، ولكنه في هذا المثال، دائمًا علامة استفهام.
If you train a model across the United States,
إذا قمت بعمل نموذج في الولايات المتحدة الأمريكية،
everybody from the state of Washington will have age question mark.
فإن كل شخص من ولاية واشنطن سيكون لديه علامة استفهام للعمر.
You're going to fill in the average age into the application.
وسنقوم بملأ متوسط العمر في الطلب،
Let's say, 40, then you're going to believe that everybody in the state of
ولنفترض أنه 40، ومن ثم فسوف نعتقد ان كل شخص في ولاية واشنطن
Washington who is applying for a loan is age 40.
ممن يقدم على طلب الحصول على القرض هو في عمر 40 عامًا.
And that's going to introduce a systematic bias
وهذا من شأنه تقديم تحيز منهجي،
into the loan applications in the state of Washington.
في طلبات الحصول على قرض في ولاية واشنطن.
And that's going to lead to all sorts of weird behavior,
وهذا يقود بدوره إلى جميع الأنواع من السلوكيات المريبة،
unhappy people, bad predictions, bad idea.
والأشخاص غير سعداء والتنبؤات والأفكار السيئة.
So imputation like this has its pluses but
لذا فإن مثل هذا الادعاء له إيجابياته،
it's also a complicated idea because it can introduce terrible biases.
لكنه أيضًا فكرة معقدة لأنه يمكن أن يؤدي إلى تحيز رهيب.
So in the third part of this module, we're going to talk about an alternative that
ولذا فإننا في الجزء الثالث من هذه الوحدة، سنقوم بالحديث عن البديل
can address some of the challenges of the first two methods.
والذي يمكن أن يقدم بدوره بعض التحديات للطريقتين السابقتين.
[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]